boisestate.edu 2018-10-03

# Privacy Statement - Boise State University

Boise State University is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Boise State University Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the Boise State University website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## Collection of your Personal Information

Boise State University collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Boise State University also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Boise State University. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by Boise State University for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Boise State University Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Boise State University public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: Boise State University does not read any of your private online communications.

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site. Boise State University encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from Boise State University so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. Boise State University encourages you to be aware when you leave the Boise State University site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. Boise State University is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the Boise State University and Boise State University family of Web sites.

## Use of your Personal Information

Boise State University collects and uses your personal information to operate the Boise State University Web site and deliver the services you have requested. Boise State University also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Boise State University and its affiliates. Boise State University may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Boise State University does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Boise State University may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Boise State University may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Boise State University, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Boise State University does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Boise State University keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within Boise State University, in order to determine what Boise State University services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Boise State University to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Boise State University Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Boise State University or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Boise State University; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Boise State University, or the public.

## Cookies and Anonymous Identifiers

A cookie is a small data file that is written to your hard drive that contains information about your visit to a web page. Personally identifiable information is not stored in these cookies. First Party Cookies are set through the university websites directly, including the Google Analytics cookie. Third Party Cookies are set by third parties, also through the university websites.

An anonymous identifier is a random string of characters that is used for the same purposes as a cookie on platforms, including certain mobile devices, where cookie technology is not available.

If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may configure your browser not to accept them at all, or to notify and require approval before accepting new cookies. Some web pages/sites may not function properly if the cookies are turned off, or you may have to provide the same information each time you visit those pages.

## Use of Third Party Services

The university websites uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). We also use Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, part of a larger category of features known as Google Analytics Advertising Reporting Features. Google Analytics uses cookies (described above) to help the websites analyze how users use the sites. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the websites (including possibly your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google.

## Advertising

The University uses this information for Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, or Google Analytics Advertising Reporting Features. The university and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the university websites.

The university and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies to display content specific advertisements to visitors that have previously visited university websites when those visitors go to other websites.

The university and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to report how visitor ad impressions, other uses of ad services and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to university websites.

The university uses data from Google’s interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics to report, optimize and deliver interest-based advertisements.

## Opting Out of Advertising Features

Users can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads by using [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/). For more information, please visit [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

## Security of your Personal Information

While no computing environment is 100% secure, Boise State University uses best efforts to secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Boise State University secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

## Student Records

Student records are protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), federal regulations which assign rights to students and responsibilities to educational institutions regarding students’ education records. The Act governs the maintenance and release of information from those records. The University has a separate policy governing FERPA regulations. [Student Privacy FERPA](http://registrar.boisestate.edu/general-information-and-policies/student-records/ferpa/)

## Changes to this Statement

Boise State University will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect community and user feedback. Boise State University encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Boise State University is protecting your information.

## Contact Information

Boise State University welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Boise State University has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Boise State University at [privacycontact@boisestate.edu](mailto:privacycontact@boisestate.edu). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
